RAHUL RAMTEKE

ABOUT ME

I have been working with NodeJS for 2 years now. I am a functional programming enthusiast with an eye for terse code. I enjoy solving architectural problems, both at code and system level. Having said all this, at the end of the day, I love building things.

EDUCATION

Delhi Technological University

2013 - 2017

BTECH, Software Engineering

Ramjas School

2006 - 2013

90%, Topped School in Computer Science

CONTACT

Phone: 9953618281 **Blog:** iostreamer.me

Email: rahul.ramteke066@gmail.com **Github:** https://github.com/iostreamer-X

Projects: iostreamer.me/projects

SIDE PROJECTS

Awkward

A NodeJS based shell. It lets you run javascript functions on system commands.

FuncShell

An application to allow using haskell based functions in your existing shell

Zeal

A P2P livestreaming web and CLI api

EXPERIENCE

Shipsy

Software Engineer, Aug 2017 - Current

- Revamped legacy service, built architecture for multitenancy
- Revamped mongo data analytics pipeline, made it twice as efficient
- Migrated major services to Typescript
- Setup error monitoring system for the organisation
- Created a more usable and abstarct version of Apache Superset

Leaf Labs

Internship, December 2014 - January 2016

- Created live tracking app which worked without Internet and solely on SMS.
- Participated in GITEX Dubai and won first place

SKILLS

Backend Technologies

Express, Nest, Loopback, NodeJS and Event loop, TypeORM, Mongoose

Databases

MongoDB, PostgresSQL, MySQL, Redis

Cloud

AWS - EC2, S3, Fargate, Docker

Paradigms and Langauges

Functional Programming, Deep understanding of Javascript, Haskell, Category Theory